Guide to the Miguel A. Gandert Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miguel A. Gandert photographs and papers
1972-2005
WA MSS S-2964
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
14.94
(114 boxes) + 8 broadsides, 7 broadsides oversize
The collection consists of photographic prints (chiefly in black and white), contact sheets, printed material, and computer disks.
Gandert, Miguel A.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 27, 28, 87, 102, 129 (sound recordings and computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of photographs and papers that document the work of Miguel A. Gandert recording mestizo culture in the Rio Grande region of the American Southwest, including the landscapes and people of Northern New Mexico, circa 1972-2006. Many of the images depict individuals underdocumented in mainstream society, including boxers, Mexican immigrants, motorcycle gang members, teenage mothers, and urban Mexican American youth. The collection consists of photographs, including contact sheets, work prints, transparencies, and exhibition prints, as well as computer media and publications with images created by Gandert.
Material in the collection includes photographic work from college and graduate school at the University of New Mexico, circa 1972-1983, as well as his exhibitions and publications through 2006. Exhibitions documented include Boxers and Wrestlers (1977), Being With It (1979), Let's Boogie at Okie's (1980), Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience (1980-1983), Tierra O Muerte (1988), Reflexiones del Corazón (1992), Face of a Community (1994), Nuevo México Profundo (2000), and Hermanitos Comanchitos (2003).
In this guide to the collection, library staff retained Gandert's titles and spellings.
Except where noted, photographic prints in the collection are black-and-white prints. Chronological arrangements within the collection are by the image creation date not the date the photograph was printed.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Miguel Gandert on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1999-2006, and on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2003.
Arrangement
Organized into five groupings: I. September 1999 Acquisition, 1972-1999. II. May 2002 Acquisition, 1980-1999. III. November 2003 Acquisition, 1982-2001. IV. June 2005 Acquisition, 1983-2003. V. December 2006 Acquisition, 1986-2005.
Miguel A. Gandert (born 1956)
Miguel A. Gandert is an Indo-Hispano American photographer and photojournalist. Born in Española, New Mexico, Gandert earned a Master of Arts in photography from the University of New Mexico in 1983. His work has appeared in many exhibitions including the National Museum of American History at the Smithsonian in 1990, the 1993 Biennial at the Whitney Museum of American Art, and at the National Hispanic Cultural Center of New Mexico in 2000.
In 1991, Gandert became a professor at the University of New Mexico, eventually the Distinguished Professor of Communication and Journalism. In 2011 he became the director of the Interdisciplinary Film and Digital Media Program.
His publications include Pilgrimage to Chimayó: Contemporary Portrait of a Living Tradition, with Sam Howarth and Enrique R. Lamadrid (Santa Fe: Museum of New Mexico Press, 1999); Nuevo México Profundo: Rituals of an Indo-Hispano Homeland, with Enrique R. Lamadrid (Santa Fe: Museum of New Mexico Press, 2000); Hermanitos Comanchitos: Indo-Hispano Rituals of Captivity and Redemption, with Enrique R. Lamadrid (Albuquerque: University of New Mexico Press, 2003); The Plazas of New Mexico, Chris Wilson, Stefanos Polyzoides, and Jose Zelaya (San Antonio, Texas: Trinity University Press, 2011); In the Country of Empty Crosses: The Story of a Hispano Family in Catholic New Mexico, with Arturo Madrid-Barela (San Antonio, Texas: Trinity University Press, 2012); and Hotel Mariachi: Urban Space and Cultural Heritage in Los Angeles, with Catherine L. Kurland and Enrique R. Lamadrid (Albuquerque: University of New Mexico Press, 2013).
Boxers (Sports) -- Pictorial works; Gang members -- Pictorial works; Hispanic American boxers -- Pictorial works; Immigrants -- Pictorial works; Mestizos -- Pictorial works; Mexican Americans -- Pictorial works; Mexicans -- United States -- Pictorial works; Motorcycle gangs -- Pictorial works; Photographers; Photojournalists; Teenage mothers -- Pictorial works; New Mexico -- Pictorial works; Rio Grande Region (Colo.-Mexico and Tex.) -- Pictorial works; Southwest, New -- Pictorial works; Born digital; Audiovisual materials; Photographic prints; Transparencies; Videocassettes; Gandert, Miguel A.
- September 1999 Acquisition, 1972-1999; 1; 4.05; (20 boxes) + 8 broadsides
  Scope and Contents
  The September 1999 Acquisition documents Gandert's work as a student at the University of New Mexico and other projects from 1972-1999. It chiefly contains black-and-white photographic prints with a few Cibachrome color prints, as well as printed material and audiovisual material.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 27 and 28 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: Photographs, Printed Material, and Audiovisual Material.
  - Photographs
    Organized under eight headings: Two Corners of a Ring / Youth Boxing, Two Corners of a Ring / Championship Wrestling, Being With It, Ecuador, Let's Boogie at Okie's, Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience, Face of a Community, followed by a heading for Miscellaneous Prints.
    This subseries chronologically documents the photographic work of Gandert, as well as publications that reproduced his images, from 1972 to 1999.
    - Two Corners of a Ring / Youth Boxing
      Organized under two headings: Matted Prints and Unmatted Prints.
      This group of photographs come from an exhibition of portraits of young male boxers active in New Mexico.
      - Matted Prints
        Matted prints are arranged by print size: 8 inches by 10 inches and 11 inches by 14 inches.
        - 8 inches by 10 inches, Photographic prints, 8 x 10 inches, dry mounted in mats, 11 x 14 inches
          - Untitled photographs, 1976; 25 (Box 1)
        - 11 inches by 14 inches, Photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
          Arranged alphabetically.
          - Boxer and Coach, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 May (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - Boxer Portrait # 2, 1976 (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - Boxer With Bloodied Nose and Trainer, 1976 (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - Boxing Gym, 1976 (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - Chris Linson, Phil Gurate, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1976 May (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - Victor In Corner, 1976 (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - Victor Romero With Cracked Wall, 1976 (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - The Winner, 1976 (Box 2 (Oversize))
          - Untitled photographs, 1976-1977; 3 (Box 2 (Oversize))
      - Unmatted Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
        - John Sanchez, 1976 (Box 1)
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 8 (Box 1)
    - Two Corners of a Ring / Championship Wrestling
      This group of photographs come from an exhibition of portraits of professional wrestlers active in New Mexico.
      - Matted Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
        - Chavo Guerrero, Wrestler, Civic Auditorium, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 September (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - Cyclone Negro, 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - Early Dawn, 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - The Hangman, 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - The Hangman #2, 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - "Hillibilly Pete", 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - Rip, "the Ripper Havok", 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - Tank Patten, 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
        - Wrestling Fan With Dragon Tattoo, 1977 (Box 3 (Oversize))
      - Unmatted Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
        - Chavo Guerrero, 1977 (Box 4 (Oversize))
        - Ox Baker, 1977 (Box 4 (Oversize))
        - Ralph, the Bell, Timekeeper, 1977 (Box 4 (Oversize))
        - Reggie Parks, 1977 (Box 4 (Oversize))
        - Tank Patten, circa 1977 (Box 4 (Oversize))
    - Being With It
      Organized under three headings: Matted Prints, Unmatted Prints, and Cibachrome Color Prints.
      This group of photographs come from an exhibition of portraits of carnival employees at the New Mexico State Fair in Albuquerque.
      - Matted Prints
        - Betty Meavy, 1979 September (Box 5 (Oversize))
        - Carny, 1979 September (Box 5 (Oversize))
        - Carny at Balloon Toss, 1979 (Box 5 (Oversize))
        - Carny With Baseball, 1979 September (Box 5 (Oversize))
        - Carny With Machine Gun, 1979 September (Box 5 (Oversize))
        - Carny With Stuffed Gorilla, 1979 September (Box 5 (Oversize))
        - Carny Women, 1979-1980; 4 (Box 6 (Oversize))
        - Ticket Vendor, 1980 (Box 6 (Oversize))
        - A Tribute to Elvis, 1979 September (Box 6 (Oversize))
        - Untitled photographs, 1978, undated; 4 (Box 6 (Oversize))
      - Unmatted Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
        Titles of photographs in this group retain variant spellings by Gandert.
        - Blond Carnie Woman With Horse, 1979 September (Box 7 (Oversize))
        - Carnie Woman With Scar, 1979 September (Box 7 (Oversize))
        - Carny With Oscar the Grouch Shirt, 1977 September (Box 7 (Oversize))
        - Carny With Stuffed Gorilla, 1979 (Box 7 (Oversize))
        - Carny Women, 1979 (Box 7 (Oversize))
        - Jolynn Woods, 1979 September (Box 7 (Oversize))
        - Mickey Mouse Balloons, 1979 September (Box 7 (Oversize))
      - Cibachrome Color Prints
        - Matted Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
          - Albuquerque, 1979 (Box 8 (Oversize))
          - Carny With Stuffed Dogs, 1980 September (Box 8 (Oversize))
          - Cholo With Tattoo, 1981 September (Box 8 (Oversize))
          - High Striker, 1980 September (Box 8 (Oversize))
          - Rope Ladder, 1981 September (Box 8 (Oversize))
          - Tidal Wave, 1980 September (Box 8 (Oversize))
          - Two Women, 1980 September (Box 8 (Oversize))
        - Unmatted Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches and smaller
          - Untitled photographs, undated; 5 (Box 7 (Oversize))
    - Let's Boogie at Okie's, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
      This group of photographs comes from an exhibition that depicts clientele at Okie's, a drinking establishment near the University of New Mexico campus in Albuquerque.
      - Chilton Gregory, 1980 May (Box 9 (Oversize))
      - Eighteen Year Old Woman With Pinball Machines, 1980 May (Box 9 (Oversize))
      - Indian Man, 1980 May (Box 9 (Oversize))
      - Man and Woman With Ripped Off Sign, 1980 May (Box 9 (Oversize))
      - Okie's Confrontation, 1980 May (Box 9 (Oversize))
      - Okie's Last Nite, the Air Was Charged, 1980 May (Box 9 (Oversize))
      - Okie's People, 1980 May (Box 9 (Oversize))
      - Phil Doyle, Okie's Bartender, 1980 May (Box 10 (Oversize))
      - "Red" Bouncer, Pool Hustler, 1980 May (Box 10 (Oversize))
      - Rockin' at Okie's, 1980 May (Box 10 (Oversize))
      - Smiling Lady With Eyes, 1980 May (Box 10 (Oversize))
      - Terry, Indian Bo Derek, 1980 May (Box 10 (Oversize))
      - Terry With Speedy Gonzales Tattoo, 1980 (Box 10 (Oversize))
      - Woman in Okie's Phone Booth, 1980 (Box 10 (Oversize))
    - Ecuador, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
      This group of photographs documents daily life in Ecuador, including street musicians and street vendors, as well as scenes from a cockfight.
      - Boletero, Otavalo, Ecuador, 1981 (Box 11 (Oversize))
      - Calzado Atlantico, Quito, Ecuador, 1981 (Box 11 (Oversize))
      - Muchachita, Quito, Ecuador, 1981 (Box 11 (Oversize))
      - Peleo del Gallo, Otavalo, Ecuador, 1981; 3 (Box 11 (Oversize))
      - Shoeshine, Riobamba, Ecuador, 1981 (Box 11 (Oversize))
      - Tiempo para Banar, El Panacillo, Ecuador, 1980 (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience, This group of material consists of Cibachrome color prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, mounted in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
      This group of photographs comes from an exhibition that documents one of the oldest and largest Spanish-speaking communities in Albuquerque, New Mexico, at the National Museum of American History, Washington, D.C., April 3-June 30, 1990.
      - Untitled photographs, 1982-1983; 6 (Box 12 (Oversize))
    - Face of a Community, This group of material consists of Polaroid prints, 22 inches by 33 inches.
      This group of photographs comes from an exhibition of portraits of members of the Hispanic community in Boston, Massachusetts.
      Arranged alphabetically by surname.
      - Pepe Gutiérrez, 1994; 2 (Box 13 (Broadside))
      - Frances and Manuel López, 1994; 3 (Box 14 (Broadside))
      - Melinda Lopez, 1994; 2 (Box 15 (Broadside))
      - Moises Morales, 1994; 4 (Box 16 (Broadside))
      - Lydia Polanco Peña, 1994; 3 (Box 17 (Broadside))
      - Jorge Quiroga, 1994 (Box 18 (Broadside))
      - José Vasquez, 1994; 2 (Box 19 (Broadside))
      - Portraits of a man, 1994; 3 (Box 20 (Broadside))
    - Miscellaneous Prints
      This group of photographs consists chiefly of portraits of individuals from New Mexico.
      - Matted Prints
        Organized under two headings by print size: 8 inches by 10 inches and Smaller, and 11 inches by 14 inches and Smaller.
        - 8 inches by 10 inches and Smaller, Photographic prints, 8 x 10 inches and smaller, dry mounted in mats, 11 x 14 inches.
          - 1972
            - Debbie, Quito, Ecuador, 1972 (Box 21)
          - 1973
            - Old Man, Cuicocha, Ecuador, 1973 (Box 21)
          - 1974
            - Bent Stop Sign, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Duelity, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Ed Leek, Artist, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Gas Station, Holman, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Grandma & Grandpa, Mora, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Kid at Lobo Office, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Lichenstein Circus, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Man Sitting in Park, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
            - Ted Kennedy, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 21)
              Portrait of Senator Edward M. "Ted" Kennedy.
          - 1975
            - Johanna, 1975 (Box 21)
            - Part of Bi-Centennial Series, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1975 (Box 21)
            - Rio la Casa, New Mexico, 1975 (Box 21)
            - Stone on Stump, Holman, New Mexico, 1975 (Box 21)
            - Wool Hat, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1975 (Box 21)
            - Untitled, 1975; 4 (Box 21)
          - 1976
            - Angelo Barela, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 (Box 21)
            - Untitled, 1976; 2 (Box 21)
          - 1977
            - Albuquerque Flea Market, 1977
          - Undated
            - Untitled photographs, undated; 26 (Box 21)
            - Untitled photographs, 4 (Box 23)
        - 11 inches by 14 inches and Smaller, Photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
          - Elaine, Barmaid, Jack's Lounge, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 November (Box 22 (Oversize))
          - Judge in New Mexico, undated (Box 22 (Oversize))
          - Judge, probably in New Mexico, undated (Box 22 (Oversize))
          - Stripper With Knit Stockings, 1977 (Box 22 (Oversize))
          - Terry, Bennie's Billiards, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 March (Box 22 (Oversize))
          - Waitress, 1976 December (Box 22 (Oversize))
          - Woman With Parrot Tattoo, Spikes Tattoo Shop, Tucson, Arizona, 1978 January (Box 22 (Oversize))
      - Unmatted Prints
        General
        This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches and smaller
        - 1973
          - Hitchhiker, Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1973 (Box 23)
        - 1974
          - Ed Leek, Artist, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1974 (Box 23)
        - 1975
          - Babe Rainbow, Tattoo Artist, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1975 (Box 23)
          - Johanna, 1975 (Box 23)
          - Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1975 (Box 23)
        - 1976
          - Angelo Barela, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 (Box 23)
          - Dishwasher, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 (Box 23)
          - Mona Kay, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 (Box 23)
          - Street Performer, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 (Box 23)
          - Woman in Bar, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1976 (Box 23)
        - 1977
          - Albuquerque Flea Market, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Bennie Billiards, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Child, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Film Projectionist, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Ira Jaffee and Wife, 1977; 2 (Box 23)
          - Judy Berman, Artist, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Mona, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Musicians, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Navajo Relocation Protest, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Performance Artist, 1977 (Box 23)
          - Topless Dancer, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977; 3 (Box 23)
          - Waitress, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1977; 3 (Box 23)
        - 1978
          - Art Deco Diner, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Bennie Roberts, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Debbie Friel, Aerialist, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Fina Station, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Fred Patterson, Tattoo Artist, Phoenix, Arizona, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Little Cowboy, Mora, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Luis Medina, Aerialist, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Miguel Paddilla With Midget Car, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Ralph, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Rollerskate Girl, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Sinclair Station, Peñasco, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Stanley Montoga, Heroin Addict, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Tattooed Woman, Phoenix, Arizona, 1978 (Box 23)
          - Wedding Portrait, La Petaca, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 23)
        - Undated
          - Central Avenue, Alba, New Mexico, undated (Box 23)
          - Untitled photographs, undated; 2 (Box 23)
      - Cibachrome Color Prints
        Organized under two headings by print size: 8 inches by 10 inches, and 11 inches by 14 inches.
        - 8 inches by 10 inches
          - South Broadway, Albuquerque, 1982 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - South Broadway, Albuquerque, 1983 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Waitress, Truth or Consequences, New Mexico, 1984 (Box 24 (Oversize))
        - 11 inches by 14 inches
          - '59 Chevy, South Broadway, 1982 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Campo Santo, Cubero, New Mexico, circa 1985 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Fiesta de San Lorenzo, Bernalillo, New Mexico, 1990 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Guadalupe Rael, Tomé, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Iglesia de San Francisco de Asís, Ranchos de Taos, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Iglesia de San Miguel del Vado, New Mexico, circa 1983 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Juan Roybal's House With Drying Herbs, circa 1984 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Morada, Lower Las Colonias, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Morada, Vadito, New Mexico, circa 1984 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Peñasco, New Mexico, circa 1984 (Box 24 (Oversize))
          - Santuario de Chimayó, New Mexico, 1983; 2 (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Printed Material
    This subseries consists of books, magazines, and newspaper clippings containing photographs by Gandert.
    - Publications with images by Miguel Gandert, 1982-1999, undated; 38 folders, including 3 compact discs (Box 25)
      Compact discs are stored in: Restricted Fragile Box 28. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Publications with images by Miguel Gandert, 1985-1998, undated; 9 (Box 26)
  - Audiovisual Material
    This subseries consists of audiovisual material related to Gandert, including recordings of television programs that featured him and a compact disc of traditional Hispanic songs in New Mexico with liner notes illustrated with images by him.
    Arranged chronologically.
    Boxes 27 and 28: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "KNME TV5 Albuquerque, New Mexico. Show: Miguel Gandert, Photographer. Producer: Sandy Garritano", 1986 November 5 and 8; WAMSSS2964_0001; 1; 00:21:45 (Box 27, Item barcode 39002102317428)
    - "Tesoros del Espíritu: A Portrait in Sound of Hispanic New Mexico", 1996; 3 compact discs (Box 27)
    - "Illustrated Daily. KNME-TV, New Mexico. The New Mexico Photographic Survey. Parts I and II.", undated; 1; 00:56:54; The program was recorded at a very low level. (Box 28, Item barcode 39002091392663)
- May 2002 Acquisition, 1980-1999; 2; 2.38; (27 boxes)
  The May 2002 Acquisition chronologically documents Gandert's projects and exhibitions from 1980-1999. It chiefly contains black-and-white work prints and exhibition prints as well as Cibachrome color prints.
  Organized into six subseries: Ecuador, Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience, Tierra O Muerte, Reflexiones del Corazón, Nuevo México Profundo, and Miscellaneous Prints.
  - Ecuador, This subseries consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
    This subseries depicts daily life in Ecuador, including scenes from a cockfight.
    - Ambato, Ecuador, undated (Box 29 (Oversize))
    - Peleo del Gallo, Otavalo, Ecudaor, 1981; 6 (Box 29 (Oversize))
    - Tiempo para Banar, El Panacillo, Ecuador, 1980 (Box 29 (Oversize))
    - Untitled photographs, undated; 3 (Box 29 (Oversize))
  - Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience
    Organized under three headings: Matted Prints, Unmatted Prints, and Cibrachrome Color Prints.
    This subseries consists of photographs from an exhibition that documents one of the oldest and largest Spanish-speaking communities in Albuquerque, New Mexico, at the National Museum of American History, Washington, D.C., April 3-June 30, 1990.
    - Matted Prints
      Organized under two headings by print size: 11 inches by 14 inches and 16 inches by 20 inches
      - 11 inches by 14 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
        - '51 Chevy, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 30 (Oversize))
        - "Cat Eyes," Melissa Armijo, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1984 (Box 30 (Oversize))
        - Lowrider Bicycle, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1984 (Box 30 (Oversize))
        - Macario Lucero, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 30 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 20 inches by 24 inches, except where noted.